Guide to the Wilfred Healey Stone Papers SC0975
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wilfred Healey Stone papers
1946-2004
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stone, Wilfred Healy
SC0975
17 Linear Feet
Collection largely pertains to his professional career at Stanford University and includes correspondence with former students and colleagues, committee files, class materials, lecture notes and references files on authors, and manuscripts. Some of the correspondence and manuscripts pertain to his work on E. M. Forster and the Bloomsbury group. Items of note in that category include notes from interviews with Julian Bell, Clive Bell, F. L. Lucas, Patrick Wilkinson, and Noel Annan; correspondence with David Garnett, Duncan Grant, and Noel Annan; and notes from his interviews with E. M. Forster, 1957-58. Stanford faculty among his correspondents include Robert McAfee Brown, H. Bruce Franklin, Albert and Barbara Gelpi, Arturo Islas, Diane Middlebrook, Tom Moser, Richard Scowcroft, and Albert J. Guerard. Other correspondents include William Chace, 1971-94; John O. and Mairi McCormick, 1962-2000; Jean and Stephen Parrish, 1949-2000; Lucio and Marcia Ruotolo, 1965-99; Arthur and Penelope Sale, 1960-2001; and Oliver and Gunnvor Stallybrass, 1958-2000.
Information about Access
Access: papers written by Stanford students may not be photocopied.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Wilfred Healey Stone earned his bachelor's (1941) and master's (1946) degrees in English at the University of Minnesota. He received his PhD at Harvard in 1950; he was awarded a Fulbright Grant for study at University of London in 1949. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1950 and served as director of freshman composition from 1962 to 1964. His published works include PROSE STYLE, A HANDBOOK FOR WRITERS and THE CAVE AND THE MOUNTAIN; A STUDY OF E. M. FORSTER. Stone retired in 1986 as professor emeritus.
Description of the Collection
Collection largely pertains to his professional career at Stanford University and includes correspondence with former students and colleagues, committee files, class materials, lecture notes and references files on authors, and manuscripts. Some of the correspondence and manuscripts pertain to his work on E. M. Forster and the Bloomsbury group. Items of note in that category include notes from interviews with Julian Bell, Clive Bell, F. L. Lucas, Patrick Wilkinson, and Noel Annan; correspondence with David Garnett, Duncan Grant, and Noel Annan; and notes from his interviews with E. M. Forster, 1957-58. Stanford faculty among his correspondents include Robert McAfee Brown, H. Bruce Franklin, Albert and Barbara Gelpi, Arturo Islas, Diane Middlebrook, Tom Moser, Richard Scowcroft, and Albert J. Guerard. Other correspondents include William Chace, 1971-94; John O. and Mairi McCormick, 1962-2000; Jean and Stephen Parrish, 1949-2000; Lucio and Marcia Ruotolo, 1965-99; Arthur and Penelope Sale, 1960-2001; and Oliver and Gunnvor Stallybrass, 1958-2000.
English literature -- 20th century; Stanford University. Department of English. Faculty; Franklin, H. Bruce (Howard Bruce); Wilkinson, L. P.; Ruotolo, Lucio P.; Sale, Arthur (Arthur H. J.).; Guérard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph); Scowcroft, Richard.; Stallybrass, Oliver.; Annan, Noel Gilroy Annan, Baron, 1916-2000; Middlebrook, Diane Wood; Bell, Clive; Gelpi, Albert.; Garnett, David S.; Grant, Duncan; Gelpi, Barbara Charlesworth.; Chace, William M.; Brown, Robert McAfee; Forster, E. M. (Edward Morgan); McCormick, John; Parrish, Stephen Maxfield.; Stone, Wilfred Healy; Islas, Arturo; Stone, Wilfred Healy; Moser, Thomas C.; MacInnes, Mairi.; Lucas, F. L. (Frank Laurence)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2010-002
  - Correspondence Files
    - Alden, Patricia, 1974-86 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Altick, Richard D., 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Appel, Alfred, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Arnaud, Daniel, 1967-85 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arp, Thomas, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - D’Assalenaux, Janis, 1974-76 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atkinson, Patricia, 1987-89 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Armstrong, Paul B., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Baer, Barbara, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bailey, Margery, 1957 (with note from Phillip Persky 1980) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bazin, Nancy, 1961-1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Beer, John and Jullian, 1977-84 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bender, John and Ann, 1970-71 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bevis, Linda, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Blair, Sara, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bledsoe, Cathy, 1985-88 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brattin, Joel, 1982-85 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brereton, Betty, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Brown, Andrew (Cambridge Univ. Press), 1979-95 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Brown, Emerson (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Brown, Robert McAfee and Sydney, 1975-2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bruffee, Kenneth H., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Budge, Ken, 1974-77 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Burns, Marjorie (U’Ren), 1972-77 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bush, Douglas, 1950-75 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Butcher, Bernard, 1995 [includes Butcher’s seminar paper “Stanford in Mississippi: A Foreign Country in Our Midst”] (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Carnochan, Bliss, 1971-75 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Carver, Michael, 1967-75 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Casper, Gerhard, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Comstock, Craig and Peggy, 1979-89 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Corrigan, Matt, 1968-75 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Cusic, Carla, 1982-85 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Daleski, H. M., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Das, Gour L., 1968-82 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Deane, Lyn, 1971-73 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - DeLapa, Michael, 1978-81 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - KeLeeuw, Karel [contains only an article on his death] (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Dodds, John, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Drekmeier, Charles and Margot, 1972-79 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Eggenschweiler, David, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Englander, 1966-81 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Felstiner, John, 1971-83 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ferguson, Susanne, 1972-84 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Fifer, Charles (Bud), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Fisk, Charles and Ann (Tempy), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ford, Newell, [includes draft of his Memorial Resolution), 1979-77 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Foster, John, 1974-81 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Franklin, H. Bruce and Jane, 1980-92 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Fussell, Paul [contains only photocopied article] (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Gagnier, Reginia, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gairdner, William D., 1966-99 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Gelpi, Albert and Barbara, 1972-75 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gerzina, Gretchen, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gioia, Dana, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Good, Ted, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gowen, Margaret, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Gregory, Hoosag, 1995-96 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Grommon, Al, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Hackling, Donald, 1969-81 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hanlon, Gayle, 1972-76 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Harm, Roger, 1972-75 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Harris, Dale, 1966-68 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Harris, Elisabeth Hall, 1975-77 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Harrison, Gary [undated student paper] (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Hass, Bob, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Heine, Elizabeth, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Henry, Nancy, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Herz, Judith, 1989-99 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Hessler, John, 1974-79 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Islas, Arturo, 1965-85 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Johnston, Judith, 1972-83 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Kaplan, Carola, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Kaye, Peter, 1981-90 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Keating, George T., 1962-66 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Kelvin, Norman, 1966-74 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Kennedy, David, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Kennedy, Donald and Jeanne, 1973, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Kraus, Dick, 1975-98 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Lago, Mary, 1979-84 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lazere, Donald, 1977-82 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Levertov, Denise, 1982-91 and undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Levin, David, 1964-98 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Littell, Emelen and Mel, 1984-94 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Loftis, John, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Lowenstein, Kate, 1995 (letter to Kate recounting Al Lowenstein in Mississippi in the summer of 1964) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Lyman, Richard, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Materer, Timothy, 1966-83 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Matthias, John, 1965-71 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - McClure, John, 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mellor, Anne, 1972-73 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Middlebrook, Diane, 1972-84 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Morgan, Susan, 1978-98 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Moore, John, 1963-75 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Moser, Tom, 1962-97 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Newsome, Bill, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Packer, Nancy, 1970 and undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Pauling, Linus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Pearkes, Tim, 1982-83 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Pease, Otis, 1982-86 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pelton, Claire, 1975-77 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Polhemus, Rob (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Pottle, Ken [student paper 1986] (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Pratt, Branwen (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Rebholz, Ron (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Robitcheck, Trude, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Rosecrance, Barbara, 1980-83 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Saxton, Ruth, 1975-83 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Schaefer, Josephine, 1959-68 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Scowcroft, Richard, 1978-2002 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Sensabaugh, George, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Shahane, V. A., 1978-82 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Shewan, Rodney, 1972-85 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Simpson, Claude, 1970-76 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Stauffacher, Jack and Josephine, 1969-93 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Steffey, Mara, 1962-64 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Stegner, Wally and Mary, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Stoll, Rae H., 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Stolz, Harry P. (Rear Admiral) and Mrs. Stolz [copies of letters objecting to the use of Stone and Hoopes’ book Form and Thought in Prose], 1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Stone, Humphrey and Solveig, 1971, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Swerdlow, Irwin and Dorothy, 1964-77 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Super, Robert, 1972, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Thompson, John H., 1965-71 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tillotson, Arthur, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Vellacott, Philip H., 1965-85 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Viswanathan, Meera, 1980-84 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Warhol, Robyn (Housley), 1980-87 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Warren, Peter, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Watt, Ian [articles and 1 card from Ruth Watt 1994] (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Weatherhead, Kingsley, Ingrid [wife] and Andrea [daughter], 1982-98 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Webb, Igor, 1966-74 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Wee, David, 1965-78 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Wessels, Norman, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Willey, Basil, 1965-83 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Williams, Raymond, articles on and notes, correspondence 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Williams, Trevor, 1996-99 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Wilson, Neville, 1969-78 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Winters, Yvor [Winters’ comment on a Robert Lowell poem and Stone’s comment on Winters, both undated] (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Wisney, Lenore [married name: Horowitz], 1969-82 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Wong, Sau-Ling Cynthia, 1975-86 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Wright, Andrew, 1966, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Wright, Gordon, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Zaniello, Thomas, 1972-77 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Bloomsbury interviews – text of article and related correspondence, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bloomsbury interviews – Julian Bell, Clive Bell, F. L. Lucas, Patrick Wilkinson, Noel Annan, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bloomsbury – David Garnett correspondence, 1965-70, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bloomsbury – Nathaniel Webb memoirs, copied in King’s College Cambridge Library (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bloomsbury – Duncan Grant correspondence, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Allen, Charles and Elsie, 1957-99 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Annan, Noel and Gabrielle, 1957-71, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cairnie, Gordon, 1955-73 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chace, William and JoAn, 1971-94 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Darlington, Beth, 1972-98 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Darlington, Beth, undated with clippings and a photograph (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Dekker, George and Lindajo Bartholomew, 1972-90 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Delaney, Paul, 1987-98 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Frulla, Guelfo, 1987-90 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Gardner, Philip G., 1980-2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Guerard, Albert J., correspondence 1967-91 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Guerard, Albert J., photocopied articles (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Guerard, Maclin, photocopied articles (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - McCormick, John O. and Mairi, 1962-2000 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - McCormick, John O. and Mairi, 1962-2000 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - McNelis, James I. and Mary, 1962-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - North, Robert and Dorothy, 1990-2002 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Parrish letters: Stone’s statement re, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Parrish, Jean, 1949-84 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Parrish, Stephen, 1949-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Parrish-Stone correspondence, copies (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Parish: Stone’s letters to, 1950-57 and 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Richards, Tom and Nan, 1984-95 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Richards, Tom and Nan, 1984-95 (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Ruotolo, Lucio and Marcia, 1965-99 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sale, Arthur, 1960-66 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sale, Arthur and Penelope, 1991-94 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sale, Arthur and Penelope, 1995-2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Sale, Arthur: correspondence with Robert Rickard re possible publication of his letters, 2001, and copies of a random sampling of Sale’s letters to Stone (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Sale, Arthur: Stone’s letters to, 1959-88 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Sale, Bevis and Jonathan, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Shepard, Roger and Barbaranne, 1971-2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Shepard, Roger and Barbaranne – clippings, articles (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Stallybrass correspondence: Wil Stone’s statement regarding, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Stallybrass, Oliver, letters from with a few replies, 1958-76 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Stallybrass, Oliver and Gunnvor, 1958-73 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Stallybrass, Oliver and Gunnvor, 1974-78 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Stallybrass, Gunnvor, 1978-88 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Stallybrass, Gunnvor, 1990-92 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Stallybrass, Gunnvor and Anne, 1994-2000 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Stallybrass, Oliver: correspondence from others regarding, 1978-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wong, David T. K., 1954, 1976-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Wyman, Willard and Jane, 1966-97 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Wyman Fund [for aluminum burro boxes for pack trips] 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961-91 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961-91 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Professional Papers
    - Program for faculty renewal “Bloomsbury Group Reunion Conference” 1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, correspondence and applications, 1971-74 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Committee on Academic Appraisal and Achievement, 1973-75 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - American Council of Learned Societies [ACLS], application, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - ACLS correspondence and applications, 1965-73 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Admissions Committee 1958-63 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - British Studies, Pacific Coast Conference on, 1975-76 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Committee on Research Policy 1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Committee on Student Services and Affairs 1961-63 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Concordia University, correspondence 1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - ETS Advanced Placement reading, June 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Fulbright Grants (Stone’s own) 1949 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Fund for the Advancement of Education, Ford Grant, 1953-56 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - General Studies Committee [Stone’s proposals to] 1957 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Guggenheim application and correspondence, 1963-72 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Guggenheim Award 1956-60 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Guggenheim Award 1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Executive Comm. Of Academic Council 1963 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Honors Tutorial 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Job offers and “nibbles” [letters of inquiry], 1949-75 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lilly Endowment, Indianapolis, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Lilly reunion 1977 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Lilly [workshops] 1976-83 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Lilly reunion 1979-80 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Low income housing [letter re interest in] 1970 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Mailing lists [in connection with Stone’s publications] – Short Story, Prose Style (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - University of Massachusetts correspondence, 1955-72 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Mellon Committee Winter 1983 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Mellon workshop evaluations 1981 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Mellon workshop reunion, 1982, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Mellon workshop, July 27-Aug. 7, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - MLA and jobs, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - NEH seminar class meetings 1980 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - NEH Summer Seminar, letters to/from applicants 1980 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - NEH Summer Seminar, graduation, poems, papers, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - NEH Summer Seminar, budget (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - NEH Battenfeld, David H., 1980-84 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - NEH Boegeman, Margaret B., 1980-84 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - NEH Boyle, Anthony J., 1980-84 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - NEH Greenberg, Lynne F., 1980-81 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - NEH Inglehart, Babette F., 1980-85 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - NEH Larschan, Richard J., 1980-88 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - NEH Lucas, Nancy, 1986-2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - NEH Lund, Michael C., 1980-85 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - NEH MacDougall, James, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - NEH Pryzant, Peggy E., 1980-84 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - NEH Rogers, Mary F., 1980-84 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - NEH Walsh, Kathleen, 1980-85 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - NEH Ward, Robert J., 1980-86 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, text of Stone’s talk “Violence and the Intellectual” and correspondence re publishing, 1980-81 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Reviews for publishers, 1988-97 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Rockefeller grant, letter of notification, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Sabbatical year, correspondence, 1964-65 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - President’s Student Advisory Committee on Academic Affairs, 1959-60 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - San Francisco Chamber of Commerce 1973 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Santa Cruz (U.C.) correspondence, 1966-68 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Stanford-in-Italy, 1966-67 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Stanford Humanities Center (application) 1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Progressive Alliance 1983 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Student Conduct Legislative Council, 1983-84 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Supplementary research grants 1963-64 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Talks (various) 1980-82 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Theme House debate 1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Hawaii, University of, correspondence 1972-73 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Tulane University, correspondence 1955-56 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - United States International University (USIU) [appraisal visit] 1971 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Vanderbilt University, correspondence 1977 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Washington University, St. Louis, correspondence 1960 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Author Files [class notes on or materials about]
    - Matthew Arnold (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - George Bassani (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Samuel Beckett (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Emily Bronte (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Anthony Burgess (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Edmund Burke (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Samuel Butler (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Italo Calvino (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Thomas Carlyle (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Joyce Cary (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Joseph Conrad (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - William Cobbett (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - J. M. Coetzee (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Wilkie Collins (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Robertson Davies (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hilda Doolittle (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - George Eliot (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Henry Fielding (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Ford Madox Ford (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - John Fowles (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Natalia Ginzburg (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - William Golding (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Nadine Gordimer (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Graham Greene (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Thomas Hardy (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Gerald Manley Hopkins (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - James Joyce (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - D. H. Lawrence (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - D. H. Lawrence – reviews (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Doris Lessing (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Carlo Levi (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Primo Levi (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Herman Melville (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - J. Stuart Mill (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Iris Murdoch (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Vladimir Nabokov (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Walter Pater (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Theodore Roethke (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - John Ruskin (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - J. D. Salinger (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Sir Walter Scot (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bernard Shaw (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ignazio Silone (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - H. O. Sturgis (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Italo Svevo (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Giovanni Verga (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Patrick White (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Oscar Wilde (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - William Wordsworth (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - William Butler Yeats (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Course Files
    - Lawrence and Forster, English 358C, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Fiction and the Market Society, English 304B, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Fiction and the Market Society, English 304C, Spring 1983 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Capitalism and Literature, English 364B, 1973-77 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Modern British Writers, English 119, 1980-84 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - English Masterpieces, English 7, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - English Masterpieces, English 7, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Files for Stone’s article “The Play of Chance and Ego in Daniel Deronda” published in Nineteenth-Century Literature, 53 June 1998
    - Articles on gambling, etc. (1) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Articles on gambling, etc. (2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Articles on gambling, etc. (3) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Proofreading of final manuscript (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Early versions of article (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Later versions of article (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Notes on gambling and debt (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1986-97 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - E. M. Forster and Bloomsbury Materials
    - Articles and off-prints dealing with E. M. Forster (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Basileona from EMF’s scrapbooks (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Four Apostles, dealing with McTaggart, Wedd, G. E. Moore, Fry [chapter eliminated from The Cave and the Mountain] (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Angela Garnett and Richard Garnett (includes photographs), 1996-97 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Forster Conference, Montreal, financial records, May 1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - E. M. Forster Seminar, English 388A, 1989, and English 100, circa 1981 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Interviews with E. M Forster [Stone’s questions & notes] 1957-58 and correspondence re publication of related articles in Twentieth Century Literature, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lecture notes: A Room with a View (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Lecture notes: Howards End and A Passage to India (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes and other things used at Stanford in Italy, Florence, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Notes on EMF for the unfinished “money book” (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Talk on EMF at Southern Oregon State College, Feb. 1984 (Box 17, Folder 13)